Guide to the Richard C. Bell Drawings and Other Materials
Richard C. Bell Drawings and Other Materials
- Drawings, 1924-2004
  - Weyerhaeuser Company, 1987-1988 (Tube 198)
    Bell Design Group; Pitt County (N.C.)
  - Weyerhaeuser Company, 1987 (Tube 204)
    Bell Design Group; Bell-Glazener Design Group; Pitt County (N.C.)
  - White Oak High School (1 of 2), 1968 (Tube 164)
    Design development drawings
    Jesse M. Page & Associates; Richard C. Bell Associates; Onslow County (N.C.)
  - White Oak High School (2 of 2), 1968 (Tube 723)
    Design Development Plan, Schematic Site Studies, Schematic Site Plan
    Richard C. Bell Associates; Jesse M. Page & Associates; Onslow County (N.C.)
  - White (Monty and Nancy) residence, 1985-1986 (Tube 745)
    Dock and Gazebo
  - White (Monty and Nancy) residence, 1984 (Tube 744)
    Master Land Plan
  - White (Monty and Nancy) residence, 1985 (Tube 508)
    Site Plan, Master Land Plan
    Meyers-Greeson Architecture-Interior Design, PA; Bell Design Group; Wake County (N.C.)
  - Wilkes Development Corporation, 1968 (Tube 321)
    Proposed zoning map, proposed land use map, planting map
    Richard C. Bell Associates; Wilkesboro (N.C.)
  - Wilkes Development Corporation, 1965 (Tube 719)
    Study Plan, Site Maps and Plans
  - Wilkes Development Corporation, 1970 (Tube 687)
    Preliminary site study
  - Wilkinson (Howard and Joan) residence (1 of 3), 1984-1991 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Floor plans, Dam and standpipe detail
    Bell Design Group; Lee Elizabeth B.; Pinehurst (N.C.)
  - Wilkinson (Howard and Joan) residence (2 of 3), 1984-1991 (Tube 626)
    Landscape Development, Grading and Drainage, Topography, Staking Plans, Site Plans, Lighting Plans, Electrical Plan, General Planting Plan, Bridge Plan and Section
    Lee Elizabeth B.; Bell Design Group; Pinehurst (N.C.)
  - Wilkinson (Howard and Joan) residence (3 of 3), 1984-1991 (Tube 627)
    Electrical Plans, Lighting Plans, Landscape Development, Staking Plan, Grading and Drainage Plans, Preliminary Elevations, Plot with Roof, Lower Level Floor Plan, Sections and Elevations
  - Wilkinson (Howard and Joan) residence (1 of 2), 1991 (Tube 106)
    Details, lighting plan
  - Wilkinson (Howard and Joan) residence (2 of 2), 1991 (Tube 628)
    General Planting Plans, Specific Planting Plan, Finished Grading and Roof Drainage Plan, Site Plans, Detail Sheet
  - Wilkinson (Howard and Joan) residence, 1999 (Tube 90)
    Rehabilitation plan
  - Wilkinson (Howard and Joan) residence, 1985-1999 (Tube 198)
    Grading and drainage plan, planting plan, detail sheet, rehabilitation plan
    Bell-Glazener Design Group; Bell Design Group; Pinehurst (N.C.)
  - Wilkinson (Howard and Joan) residence (Tube 67)
  - Wilkinson (Howard and Joan) residence, 2000 (Tube 91)
    Main entrance garden
  - Wilkinson (Howard and Joan) residence (Tube 204)
    Landscape planting plan
  - Wilkinson (Howard and Joan) residence, 1985-1991 (Tube 68)
    Details, main entrance garden, staking plan, planting plan, general irrigation plan
    Lee Elizabeth B.; Bell Design Group; Bell-Glazener Design Group; Pinehurst (N.C.)
  - William (Mr. and Mrs. Turner) residence, 1968 (Tube 477)
    Landscape plan, details, plant lists
    F. Carter Williams, Architects; Raleigh (N.C.)
  - Williams (Mr. and Mrs. F. Carter), 1963-1964 (Tube 723)
    Planting Plan, Site Plan and Details, Preliminary Landscape Plan
  - Willis Title (Tube 97)
    Site development, landscape
  - Willson (Joe and Jo Carole) residence, 1977 (Tube 113)
    Planting plan, staking, grading, landscape plan
  - Willson (Joe and Jo Carole) residence (Tube 115)
  - Wilmington/Blount Street parking deck (1 of 9), 1990 (Tube 383)
    Lighting controls, telephone riser diagrams, landscape site improvements, ramp anti-icing plan, Wilmington Street entrance/exit, functional plans
  - Wilmington/Blount Street parking deck (2 of 9), 1990 (Tube 388)
    Site plan, site utilities, level plans, building elevations, structural framing plan, Morgan Street elevation
  - Wilmington/Blount Street parking deck (3 of 9), 1990 (Tube 187)
    Level one and four plans, topographic survey, site utilities, structural framing plan, functional layout
  - Wilmington/Blount Street parking deck (4 of 9), 1990 (Tube 237)
    landscape site improvements, site utilities, level one and four plans, building elevations, building and wall sections, foundation plan, framing plan, plumbing and fire protection, lighting plan, power riser diagram, functional plans
  - Wilmington/Blount Street parking deck (5 of 9), 1990 (Tube 346)
    Property map, parking deck plan at street level, schematic design plan, selected preliminary concept, alternate concept
  - Wilmington/Blount Street parking deck (6 of 9), 1990 (Tube 609)
    Site plan, deck plans, elevations
  - Wilmington/Blount Street parking deck (7 of 9), 1990 (Tube 610)
    Scheme B, site plan, level plans, elevations, axonometric, site utilities, structural framing plan
  - Wilmington/Blount Street parking deck (8 of 9), 1990 (Tube 611)
    Site plan, site utilities, level plans, elevations, structural framing plan alternates, functional layout
  - Wilmington/Blount Street parking deck (9 of 9), 1990 (Tube 612)
    Elevations, level plans, site plan, sketches
  - Wilmington/Blount Street parking deck (1 of 10), 1991 (Tube 381)
    Foundation plan, retaining wall details, level framing plans, column schedule, beam schedule, slab sections, wall sections, stair and elevator plans
  - Wilmington/Blount Street parking deck (2 of 10), 1991 (Tube 382)
    Stair plans, elevator plans, pedestrian bridge, electrical site plan, lighting plan
  - Wilmington/Blount Street parking deck (3 of 10), 1991 (Tube 384)
    Demolition plan, staking plan and entrance drive profiles, utilities and drainage, staking plan, grading/drainage plan, planting plan, construction details, ramp anti-icing plan, level plans, elevations
  - Wilmington/Blount Street parking deck (4 of 10), 1991 (Tube 385)
    Elevations, building section, pedestrian bridge, ticket booth plan, wall sections, plans and sections, door schedules and details, handrail and guardrail details, roof and canopy details, foundation plan, retaining wall details, framing plan
  - Wilmington/Blount Street parking deck (5 of 10), 1991 (Tube 386)
    Framing plans, beam schedule and details, slab sections, typical slab layouts and details, wall sections, stair and elevator plans, pedestrian bridge, canopy framing, canopy specifications
  - Wilmington/Blount Street parking deck (6 of 10), 1991 (Tube 387)
    Storm drain, plumbing, fire protection plans, electrical site plan, lighting plans, electrical plans, lighting controls and schedule
  - Wilmington/Blount Street parking deck (7 of 10), 1991 (Tube 169)
    Ground level functional plan, grading and drainage plan, topographic survey, planting plan, construction details, staking plan
    Burnstudio Architects; Wilbur Smith Associates, Inc.; Bell-Glazener Design Group; Raleigh (N.C.)
  - Wilmington/Blount Street parking deck (8 of 10), 1991 (Tube 353)
    Schedule of sheets, demolition plan, utilities and drainage, level plans, foundation plan, retaining wall details, column schedule, stair and elevator foundations
    Burnstudio Architects; Bell-Glazener Design Group; Wilbur Smith Associates, Inc.; Raleigh (N.C.)
  - Wilmington/Blount Street parking deck (9 of 10), 1991 (Tube 354)
    Master plan, site plan, functional plan, retaining wall details, utilities and drainage
  - Wilmington/Blount Street parking deck (10 of 10), 1991 (Tube 355)
    Level plans, elevations, wall sections
  - Wilmington/Blount Street parking deck (Tube 238)
    Framing plan, landscape site improvement, functional plan, parking deck plan at street level
  - Windsor Court: Land use and subdivision plan, 1988 (Tube 30)
    Jack and Lucy Finch - owners
  - Winston (Mr. and Mrs. Charles M.) residence, 1966-1969 (Tube 347)
    Landscape plan, landscape development, planting plan
  - Winston (Mr. and Mrs. Charles M.) residence, 1969 (Tube 351)
  - Winston-Salem topographic map, 1962 (Tube 581)
    Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation; Winston-Salem (N.C.)
  - Wood Hollow Country Homes (1 of 5), 1977 (Tube 300)
    Schematic concept plan
  - Wood Hollow Country Homes (2 of 5), 1977 (Tube 427)
    First floor lighting plan, garage and foundation plan, floor plans, typical sections, elevations
  - Wood Hollow Country Homes (3 of 5), 1977 (Tube 428)
    Bird's eye view, typical foundation plan, basement plans and sections, floor plans, sections and details, cross section, basement lighting plan
  - Wood Hollow Country Homes (4 of 5), 1977 (Tube 512)
    Site Plan, Typical First Floor Plan, Basement Plan and Sections, Typical Foundation Plan, First Floor Lighting Plan, Basement Lighting Plans, Typical Cross Section, Sections and Detail
  - Wood Hollow Country Homes (5 of 5), 1977 (Tube 581)
  - Wood Hollow Country Homes (Tube 580)
    Birds-eye view of typical unit
  - Wood Hollow Country Homes: River Ridge Run, 1977 (Tube 35)
  - WRAL-101 FM structure, 1981 (Tube 727)
    Structure Plan
  - WRAL-TV (Tube 785)
  - Wright (Mr. and Mrs. Thomas D., Jr.) proposed residence, 1968 (Tube 56)
    McCoy Kenneth Scott AIA; Richard C. Bell Associates; Durham County (N.C.)
  - Wright (Mr. and Mrs. Thomas D., Jr.) proposed residence: Woodlawn, 1968 (Tube 737)
    Construction Details, Plant List, Cabana Area Plans & Details, Pool Plan and Section, Grading Plan, Staking Plan, Details, Landscape Development Plans, Site Plans, Enlarged Master Site Plan
  - Wright (Mr. and Mrs. Thomas D., Jr.) residence, 1968 (Tube 814)
    Planting plan, master plan, grading plan, staking plan
    Scott Kenneth McCoy 1925-1980; Richard C. Bell Associates; Durham County (N.C.)
  - Yates Baptist Church, 1964 (Tube 698)
    Site Plan, Revised Site Plan, Planting Plan
  - Young Men's Christian Associations, 1964 (Tube 700)
  - Zimmerman (Fred and Martha) residence (1 of 2), 1998 (Tube 250)
  - Zimmerman (Fred and Martha) residence (2 of 2), 1998 (Tube 455)
  - Zip Mart #29: Stalling's Oil Co., 1998 (Tube 134)
    Proposed landscape plan
    Appian Consulting Engineers, PA; Raleigh (N.C.)
- Project Files, 1965-2002
  This series contains correspondence, contracts, financial records, product information, and photographs for a small number of Bell’s projects.
  - Bell/Glazener Design Group, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Standard Schedule of Time and Expenses, Water Garen Park, LLC, Amenities and Services
  - Ferdon (Ben and Jane) residence, 2000-2002 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Pittsboro (N.C.)
  - Fryer (John and Diana) residence (1 of 4), 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Fryer (John and Diana) residence (2 of 4), 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Fryer (John and Diana) residence (3 of 4), 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Fryer (John and Diana) residence (4 of 4), 1999 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Gugleman (Dr. Richard and Dr. Mary Lou Melville) residence, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Project Notes
  - Guilford College: Student apartments, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Kelley (Dr. Scott and Mrs. Meera) residence (1 of 2), 1994-2003 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Kelley (Dr. Scott and Mrs. Meera) residence (2 of 2), 1994-2003 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Kelley (Dr. Scott and Mrs. Meera) residence, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - King (Robert and Renee) residence, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Lea (Diane and James W.) residence, 1997-2002 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Lyday (Nancy and Russell) residence, 1965-1980 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    "Appraisal Report of Damages Due to Taking by the City of Raleigh" (1980)
  - Lyerly (Herbert Kim and Annie D.) residence, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Meadowmont of Chapel Hill, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    "Community Association Documents", "Architectural Design Guidelines and Architectural Review Committee Procedures"
  - Miscellaneous notes, ca. 1988 - 1990; 1988 1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Moore Square Station West parking facility and transit mall, 1985-1988 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Wilbur Smith Associates, Inc.; Thompson J. M.; Southern Bell Engineering Division; Bell-Glazener Design Group; Raleigh (N.C.)
  - North Carolina State College Agromeck, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - North Carolina State Museum of Natural Sciences at Raleigh, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    RWC, Inc.; Bell-Glazener Design Group; Raleigh (N.C.)
  - Parker Lancaster Corporation (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Cary (N.C.)
  - Recreation and Maintenance Facilities, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Rowland (Joe) estate: Somerhill (1 of 4), 1995-2001 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Hillsborough (N.C.)
  - Rowland (Joe) estate: Somerhill (2 of 4), 1995-2001 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Rowland (Joe) estate: Somerhill (3 of 4), 1995-2001 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Slides
  - Rowland (Joe) estate: Somerhill (4 of 4), 1995-2001 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Saint Mary's College (1 of 4), 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Saint Mary's College (2 of 4), 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    "Application for Variance before the Raleigh Board of Adjustment", "Official Agenda, Raleigh City Council"
  - Saint Mary's College (3 of 4), 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Saint Mary's College (4 of 4), 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Stevenson (Connie and Daniel) residence, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Thomas Wolfe Memorial Visitors Center, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Asheville (N.C.)
  - Thompson (John R., III) and Kohn (Steven C.) residence (1 of 2), 1997-2002 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Thompson (John R., III) and Kohn (Steven C.) residence (2 of 2), 1997-2002 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - University of North Carolina at Greensboro: Alumni House: renovation progress set: volume 1, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - University of North Carolina at Greensboro: Alumni House: renovation progress set: volume 2, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 3)